<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>PerfAudit | Performance Audit of Websites by Professionals</title>
    <description>Performance Audit of Websites by Professionals. Run Jank Free and Performant Web Applications care free.</description>
    <link>http://perfaudit.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://perfaudit.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Fri, 06 Mar 2015 04:06:25 +0530</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 06 Mar 2015 04:06:25 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v2.5.3</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>We are ON</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Hello from Perfaudit!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Perfaudit is all about Performance. We have started this project on a mission to performance audit the awesome websites that we all use now and then.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the coming days, we’ll audit these website for network performace, page rendering performance and whatever that makes a website’s user experience great.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stay tuned for some really enlightening audit from us.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 04 Mar 2015 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>http://perfaudit.com/blog/we-are-on</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://perfaudit.com/blog/we-are-on</guid>
        
        
        <category>blog</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Introduction</title>
        <description>&lt;a href=&quot;#&quot; class=&quot;image featured&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/pic01.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fringilla nisl. Donec accumsan interdum nisi, quis tincidunt felis sagittis eget.
odio eleifend. Duis commodo fringilla commodo. Aliquam erat volutpat. Vestibulum
facilisis leo magna. Cras sit amet urna eros, id egestas urna. Quisque aliquam
tempus euismod. Vestibulum ante ipsum primis in faucibus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Phasellus nisl nisl, varius id porttitor sed, pellentesque ac orci. Pellentesque
habitant morbi tristique senectus et netus et malesuada fames ac turpis egestas. Morbi
bibendum justo sed mauris vehicula malesuada aliquam elit imperdiet. Aliquam eu nibh
lorem, eget gravida mi. Duis odio diam, luctus et vulputate vitae, vehicula ac dolor.
Pellentesque at urna eget tellus lobortis ultrices sed non erat. Donec eget erat non
magna volutpat malesuada quis eget eros. Nullam sodales cursus sapien, id consequat
leo suscipit ut. Praesent id turpis vitae turpis pretium ultricies. Vestibulum sit
amet risus elit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Donec consectetur vestibulum dolor et pulvinar. Etiam vel felis enim, at viverra
ligula. Ut porttitor sagittis lorem, quis eleifend nisi ornare vel. Praesent nec orci
eget quam rutrum bibendum. Proin pellentesque diam non ligula commodo tempor. Vivamus
eget urna nibh. Curabitur non fringilla nisl. Donec accumsan interdum nisi, quis
tincidunt felis sagittis eget. Donec elementum ligula dignissim sem pulvinar non semper
odio eleifend. Duis commodo fringilla commodo. Aliquam erat volutpat. Vestibulum
facilisis leo magna. Cras sit amet urna eros, id egestas urna. Quisque aliquam
tempus euismod. Vestibulum ante ipsum primis in faucibus orci luctus et ultrices
posuere cubilia.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Phasellus nisl nisl, varius id porttitor sed, pellentesque ac orci. Pellentesque
habitant morbi tristique senectus et netus et malesuada fames ac turpis egestas. Morbi
bibendum justo sed mauris vehicula malesuada aliquam elit imperdiet. Aliquam eu nibh
lorem, eget gravida mi. Duis odio diam, luctus et vulputate vitae, vehicula ac dolor.
Pellentesque at urna eget tellus lobortis ultrices sed non erat. Donec eget erat non
magna volutpat malesuada quis eget eros. Nullam sodales cursus sapien, id consequat
leo suscipit ut. Praesent id turpis vitae turpis pretium ultricies. Vestibulum sit
amet risus elit.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 26 Feb 2015 07:25:40 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>http://perfaudit.com/blog/introduction</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://perfaudit.com/blog/introduction</guid>
        
        
        <category>blog</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>CanIUse.com</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Hello folks! This is Perfaudit’s first case study for which we chose &lt;a href=&quot;http://caniuse.com/&quot;&gt;caniuse.com&lt;/a&gt;. If you want to see us live auditing the website, checkout our video:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/embed/VyHKIMORH_k&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;h2 class=&quot;center heading&quot; id=&quot;network-profiling&quot;&gt;Network profiling&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2015/03/caniuse-pagespeed.png&quot; alt=&quot;Google pagespeed issues&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As we see, caniuse.com has a google pagespeed score of 84 which is pretty descent. There are few issues pointed out by pagespeed which are mainly due to 3rd party files not leveraging browser caching or coming unminified and uncompressed. These are mostly harmless but still can be fixed by caching these external files on the website itself so as to get full control over them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;after-load-profiling&quot;&gt;After load profiling&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;issue-janky-scrolling&quot;&gt;Issue: Janky scrolling&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On caniuse.com homepage, if you scroll down the page hovering over the list of links, you will experience occasional jerks. That is what we call a “Jank”. Lets try debugging the issue using Google Chrome’s devtool timeline. Running a quick timeline recording, we get the
following graph:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2015/03/caniuse-paint-janks.png&quot; alt=&quot;Paint janks&quot; class=&quot;full-width&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This shows that we are shooting our limit due to some paint events. Paint events happen when something needs to be drawn on the page. This means when we are scrolling while hovering over the list, something is being drawn. Yes, its those links changing their color when hovered on. If you were to inspect one of those links and enable the &lt;code&gt;:hover&lt;/code&gt; pseudo class on them, you’ll see the culprit style:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2015/03/caniuse-jank-causing-css.png&quot; alt=&quot;Jank causing CSS&quot; class=&quot;full-width&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you disable the &lt;code&gt;color&lt;/code&gt; property on &lt;code&gt;:hover&lt;/code&gt; and rerun a timeline recording, you’ll notice that there are no more paint events crossing the 60fps bar. Better performance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To solve this, there is a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.thecssninja.com/css/pointer-events-60fps&quot;&gt;neat trick&lt;/a&gt; by Ryan Seddon to listen for scroll event and disable pointer events on an element, say &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;body&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;, so that mouse dependent paints do not happen:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre class=&quot;prettyprint&quot;&gt;
	// JS
	var timeout, pointerEventsDisabled;
	window.addEventListener(&#39;scroll&#39;, function () {
		clearTimeout(timeout);
		if (!pointerEventsDisabled) {
			document.body.classList.add(&#39;no-pointer-events&#39;);
			pointerEventsDisabled = true;
		}
		timeout = setTimeout(function () {
			document.body.classList.remove(&#39;no-pointer-events&#39;);
			pointerEventsDisabled = false;
		}, 500);
	})
&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre class=&quot;prettyprint&quot;&gt;
	// CSS
	.no-pointer-events,
  .no-pointer-events * {
  	pointer-events: none !important;
  }
&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This will essentially disable the pointer events as soon as the scroll starts and enable them half a second after the last scroll event fires.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is a similar issue on their results page too. If you search something, say &lt;code&gt;transform&lt;/code&gt;, and scroll the shown &lt;a href=&quot;http://caniuse.com/#search=transform&quot;&gt;results page&lt;/a&gt; you will notice frequent janks. Lets run a recording in devtools timeline for this page. This is what we got:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2015/03/caniuse-result-page-timeline.png&quot; alt=&quot;Result page timeline&quot; class=&quot;full-width&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Notice those green coloured outburst at regular intervals. Those are heavy paint events causing the visible Jank! Again, if you were to use the above mentioned technique you would get a much smoother experience during the scroll.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That is it for this audit. If you want us to audit any specific website, do let us know in the comments or on &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/perfaudit&quot;&gt;twitter&lt;/a&gt;. We’ll definitely try to take it up as our next case study.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do not forget to follow us for more such perfy performace audits.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 26 Feb 2015 07:25:40 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>http://perfaudit.com/case-study/caniuse.com</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://perfaudit.com/case-study/caniuse.com</guid>
        
        
        <category>case-study</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
